Alexandre TANGUY

Engineering manager

Leader of IT technical teams and projects with a network and security engineer background. I am not a software engineer.



Who am I and what am I looking for?

After 8 years in the tech field, as a network and security engineer, where I learned lots of things and grow up as an engineer and a human being, I understood that I was happier leading a team and helping them to achieve big projects and grow in their skills. Moreover...

Professional experience

Engineering Manager @ OVHcloud (January 2020 - Present)

Team leader of the Network Data squad, composed of the Network Observability and the Network IPAM teams. - Point of contact for other teams and PU, for Network observability and IP related topics - Follow-up on projects - Creation of roadmaps with Program managers support - Agile methodology implementation and animation: sprint planning, daily, sprint review, retrospectives, etc.

Network engineer @ OVHcloud (Mars 2018 - January 2020)

- In charge of the design of network products - In charge of R&D on some projects - **Technologies**: BGP, VXLAN, ECMP, Cisco and Arista devices

** Network and security engineer @ Cdiscount** (January 2016 - Mars 2018)

Member of the Security team for 1 year and then the SRE team for 1 year (internal move-up). - In charge of - In charge of - Technologies: Cisco ACI, Checkpoint firewalls, F5 loadbalancers

Education and languages

TBC

Activities and interests

• Hobbies: reading (a lot!),

• **Sports**: climbing/bouldering, running, cycling.

■ Volunteering

TBC